

Phone: +961-81972024 sif.k.alam@net.usek.edu.lb Jdeideh, Matn, Lebanon

Links: GitHub LinkedIn

### PROFILE

A top computer engineering student with remarkably high grades and various work experience in various sectors. Possess excellent critical thinking and problem-solving skills alongside multilingual capabilities and a love for programming, been working in the field for the past year and keen to tackle new challenges at your company.

### **EDUCATION**

Holy Spirit University of Kaslik USEK Sep 2021 - Current

Bachelor's in Computer Engineering

Current GPA: 90.15

GGTA2 Public School Sep 2019 - June 2021

Lebanese Baccalaureate in Life Sciences

Grade: 18.4/20 Ranked 19th in Lebanon.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **QWERTY**

May 2024 - Now

# **Freelance**

May 2023 - May 2024

## **Stitches Studio**

March 2024 - May 2024

### **IEEE USEK SB**

December 2022 - December 2023

# **USEK**

October 2022 - October 2023

## **APSAD**

October 2021 - February 2022

## Lead Developer

Leading ideation and development at this exciting startup, working on various projects, providing innovative and sustainable solutions based on client needs.

### **Full stack Developer**

Built a diverse and interesting portfolio of projects using the latest technologies and best practices while interacting with clients and corporations.

### Full stack Developer

Worked in a SCRUM environment on the Education Basket Systems, using React.js and Nest.js to upgrade and maintain the existing system while writing maintainable and reliable code.

### **Active Committee Member**

Coordinated and organized IEEE events like the SYPLC 2023, while working together to tackle various budget and management problems with different organisations.

### Student Representative of the School of Engineering

Actively worked to enhance the student experience at the university. Played a vital role in the exchange rate crisis resolution.

### Social Worker

Tracked and managed all ongoing projects at one of the leading NGO in Lebanon.

### SKILLS

Next.js	Java
React.js	Tailwind CSS
Nest.js	React Native
Team Leadership	Database Management
No-Code Development	Software Engineering
Agile Development	Python